

JON-PAUL BOYD

Intelligent Systems Engineer

I thrive on delivering tangible, cutting-edge, Al-enabled and analytic solutions that inform, empower & perform. I help solve business challenges and deliver value to all stakeholders through strong theory, experienced hands-on, clarity of thought and communication.

1+41 (0)79 952 18 81

_₹ jp@corticalstack.ai

corticalstack.ai

in jonpaulboyd

ONyon, CH

EDUCATION

STATS

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

SAP HANA Technical Architect

Nestle | Vevey, CH | 2014 - 2017

Technical lead, inspiring team implementing groundbreaking HANA-based analytics reporting solution. Empowered 3000 users with multi-level recipe search to answer questions of regulatory compliance, quantity & procurement previously impossible. Learned I'm still hungry for technical challenges.

- Resolved SAP product shortcomings, developing tool for analytic privileges build & assign, enabling project go-live.
- Quantified performance, developing tool measuring query times vs KPIs, supporting user experience/expectation mamt.
- Led configuration of HANA workload management, HALM & HRF, acquiring required skillsets & sharing with team.
- Major contributor to Nestle HANA dev best practices.
- Led 5 HANA major upgrades & migration of analytics sidecar to embedded NetWeaver/HANA dual stack.
- Daily liaison with stakeholders, technical & product teams.

SAP HANA Technical Architect

Bluefin Solutions | London, UK | 2014

Helped BAT realise Gartner's Logical Data Warehouse concept by implementing HANA SDA for data federation of London & Sydney databases. Learned trust won on transparency & keeping delivery promises goes a long way.

Developed P&L with sub-second performance (legacy 2m10s), SAP Fiori KPI dashboard with line item drill-down.

SAP HANA Technical Architect

HANA Propulsion Laboratory | Blonay, CH | 2013

Learned HANA by engineering piloted vehicle, with real time telemetry to cloud-hosted dB for analytics & vehicle control via openUI5 cockpit. Realised benefits of deep & wide research.

Data mining for game analytics & achievement/reward system tied to mission objectives & pilot behaviour.

SAP Web Dynpro ABAP Consultant

Nestle | Vevey, CH | 2010 - 2013

Hired to solve skillset deficit, lead for complex development, problem-solving & upgrades. Learned greater self-belief & improved interpersonal skills through learning from others.

- Brought sophisticated recipe change doc concept to life with UI design driven by simplicity, familiarity & customisation.
- Delivered technical training for offshore teams.

SAP ABAP Consultant

Belgian Railways | Brussels, BB | 2008 – 2010

With a natural team-lead expertise, successfully rescued a failing technical project to deliver integration of RF scanning into warehouse management shipment handling. Learned love of OO dev & software in physical systems.

 Individually responsible for complex bespoke development functionality within logistics execution.

SAP ABAP Consultant

Cap Gemini | Middlesbrough, UK | 2000 – 2008

Senior ABAP dev in SAP competency centre, supporting team's flagship nearshoring service by analysing customer systems from ABAP perspective to enable the smooth transitioning to SAPrun support. Further demonstrated technical & client-facing capability by delivering additional revenue earning on-site consultancy & training. Learned rewards of coaching juniors.

- Work pipeline management and assignment, training and support of 3 ABAP developer colleagues.
- Innovated systems integration monitoring dashboard.

Masters Intelligent Systems

De Montfort University | UK | 2017 - 2020

Discovered why stronger partnerships should exist between enterprise and academia.

- Applied Computational Intelligence (88%) Predicting customer behaviour with treebased classifiers. Extensive Python with data profiling & preparation, unsupervised & supervised machine learning, overfitting protection, hyperparameter tuning, model scoring, evaluation & selection.
- A.I. Programming (80%) NLP Python NLTK context-free grammars for natural language to SQL database query.
- Data Mining (80%) Data analysis & machine learning to predict risk indicators for cardiovascular disease.
- Neural Networks (80%) Evaluation of biomass & classification of network activity (intrusion, attack, normal).
- Fuzzy Logic (94%)

Classifying breast cancer tumours with fuzzy inference system, outperforming neural networks. Paper being submitted to journal of Applied Soft Computing for publication.

Research Methods (96%) PhD proposal for augmented analytics.

Mobile Robots (97%)

Virtual search & rescue robot controlled via Python, implementing obstacle avoidance, sensor data fusion, environment mapping, precision navigation, victim location.

- Optimization Computational Intelligence (100%) Design & build of Python-based hyper-heuristic optimization platform to address the real-world problem of scheduling optimisation. 5 example nature-inspired metaheuristic algorithms are implemented. A hyper-heuristic feature dynamically switches low-level metaheuristics deterministically use the most appropriate algorithm according to current problem state, or select one stochastically.
- Masters Project In Progress

Building cloud-hosted medical research for knowledge discovery, cockpit summarization, classification topic & clustering for best-informed next stage research actions, using COVID-19 literature.

"Tech savvy, experienced, meticulous, dependable, ingenious & eager to learn more" Rudi Dutli, Principal, Infosys Lodestone

"Builds comprehensive understanding of architectures involved, educating & inspiring teams & co-workers in the process. A real flair for challenging, on-the-edge development" Trond Stroemme, Team Lead, SAP App Expertise Centre, Nestle

"An expert in his domain, a great team player. His focus on results with optimal quality is outstanding"

Norbert Rignall, Master Data Solution Architect, Nestle

23

LinkedIn **Recommendations**

Years software dev

Years HANA dev

36

Companies provided expertise

GitHub Repos

Masters modules graded distinction

Times consulting contract extended

Individual delivering client centric excellence

TOOLS

Python Pandas Numpy Scikit-Learn Keras NLTK Elasticsearch MongoDB SAP HANA SAP ABAP SAP Security React.IS JavaScript 5 4 1 Amazon AWS MS Azure Docker Git GitLab Linux Windows 10

AWARDS

Microsoft Certified Azure **Fundamentals**

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner